PRATHIMA GOPAL KRISHNA

201, Indiana Avenue, Apt 329C, Lubbock, Texas, 79415 Phone: 806-470-9798 | Email: prathikri@gmail.com | Website:

http://prathimagopalkrishna.github.io/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

Skilled Full Stack Java Developer offering 7 years of experience in delivering enterprise applications with successful expertise in using new tools and technical developments to drive enhancements across an entire SDLC process. Proven leadership skills and ability to work individually and function as a team player.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

03/2015- Present: Graduate Research Assistant, Texas Tech University.

- Evaluated the resilience and impact of disasters on network critical interdependent system by designing a framework and simulating an agent based model of the framework.
- Demonstrated that a multi-drop framework is secure and resilient to attacks.

08/2011 -07/2014: Svc Information Developer I, Hewlett-Packard Global Soft.

- Implemented product ordering and tracking system of the Telstra NBN application with minimum defects.
- Awarded the HP-E-Award for quick troubleshooting and resolution of defects during System Integration Testing (SIT) at onsite and offshore.
- Reduced the defect resolution time and quality improvement by minimizing the defects during User Acceptance Testing (UAT) and production release by leading and assisting the team.
- Symantec: Migrated applications across platforms to UAT and production environment.
- Reduced the build and deployment time by automating build scripts.
- Monitored and performed error free database baseline activity.

07/2010 - 08/2011: Sr. Software Engineer, IGATE Global Solutions.

- In the automated system to deduce HONDA dealer arrival date, implemented the ordering process with minimum defects.
- Led and mentored a small team of UI developers in timely delivery of the deliverables.
- Accurately captured business rules by reverse engineering the legacy system developed in COBOL.
- Ensured error free version controlling while assisting as configuration controller.

08/2007 - 07/2010: Sr. Analyst Programmer, Crimson Logic.

• Implemented and tested the guarantee and refund payment system of the single window clearance system for Qatar customs with minimum defects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Programming and Scripting Languages: Java, SQL, PL/SQL, Java script, Unix Shell scripting.

Operating System: Windows, UNIX.

Database: Oracle, IBM DB2, Microsoft SQL Server. **Framework and Web Technology:** JSF, Spring, Hibernate, Struts, HTML, CSS, JSP.

Web/Application Server: Weblogic, Websphere, Tomcat.

Software Design and Development Tool: Eclipse, Visual Studio, Visual Paradigm, StarUML. **Service and Configuration Management Tool:** Remedy, HP Quality Center, Perforce, SVN. **Analytical and Reporting Tool:** Tableau, SAS Enterprise guide, SSAS, SSIS.

Web Services: SOAP, REST, WSDL, XML.

Certification: Sun Certified Java Programmer (SCJP).

EDUCATION:

Master of Science, Management Information System

Graduation - 05/2016

Rawls College of Business Administration, Texas Tech University.

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science

Graduated in 2007

Amrita Institute of Technology and Science, Bangalore, India.